Raymond Wu

raymond.wu@carleton.ca n raymondwu1.github.io linkedin.com/in/rwu1

SUMMARY

Upcoming software engineering graduate with a passion for programming and ability to learn new technologies in a fast-paced environment. Self-motivated and proven to effectively collaborate with diverse teams to push new features and automate workflow. Strong in CI/CD and agile development. Proficient with Java, C#, JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS. Experience with AWS, Azure and SQL databases.

Software Developer Intern

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sept 2016 – Jan 2017

Quest/Dell Software Group | Kanata, Ontario

- Created Jenkins pipeline scripts and pushed updates to automate the integration, testing and deployment of source code based on feedback from the development teams
- Optimized the performance of the software build and deployment process by over 33% by implementing parallel stages and executing material work within nodes
- Developed PowerShell scripts to automate deployment of components to AWS and Azure
- Collaborated with the front-end team to automate the setup of their software environments

Junior Software Engineer

Jan 2016 - April 2016

Communications Research Centre | Nepean, Ontario

- Built an IoT testbed to analyze interference between devices using various wireless protocols
- Developed software for integrating systems and data analysis using WinForms in C#
- Implemented network analyzing software to analyze data transfer, power levels and performance between devices in an 802.11n network
- Optimized networks by over 50% by monitoring data traffic and adjusting appropriate devices

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Perk Manager App

- Developed a web application using Java and Spring MVC that allowed users to easily create and manage a profile with all their subscriptions
- Designed REST APIs and server backend to fetch and modify user data stored in PostgreSQL
- Adopted continuous integration and deployment using GitHub, Travis CI and Heroku

TFTP File Transfer

 Worked in a team to develop a file transfer system in Java that allowed concurrent clients to connect and read/write files to a server using the TFTP protocol on top of UDP

Personal Website (https://raymondwu1.github.io/)

- Developed and designed a personal website using HTML5, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Implemented smooth scrolling between page contents using JavaScript and jQuery

Front End Technologies

- Developed a calculator web application for arithmetic operations using React
- Developed games like breakout, snake and Tetris using HTML5 canvas, CSS and JavaScript
- Created a random quote generator using a public REST API and JavaScript

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java, C/C++, C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, REST API, Groovy, Spring, jQuery, React, Redux, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Git, Agile, Jenkins, PowerShell

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering | Carleton University, Canada | Sep 2013 – Nov 2018 Honors: Lester Bowles Pearson Entrance Scholarship, Dean's Honour List 2013-2014 Full Stack Web Development Certification | 1800 Hour Program | FreeCodeCamp | In progress Relevant Coursework: Responsive Web Design, JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, Front-End Libraries, Data Visualization, APIs and Microservices, Information Security and Quality Assurance